Rohan Upponi

📞 (480)-658-9741 🖾 upponirohan@gmail.com 🔟 linkedin.com/in/rohanupponi 🕥 github.com/rupponi

math rohanupponi.com

SUMMARY

Software engineer and problem solver that loves difficult challenges and learns by building. Programming primarily with Java, work experience includes professional large-scale development work with AWS with internships with Intel and STC Health. Regular personal project experience includes development of multiple Android apps and web development experience using React and GraphQL. Currently working as an associate software engineer at Capital One.

EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer at Capital One

(February 2020 - Present)

- Built Spring Boot microservices supporting Capital One's internal planning and reporting platform, freeing the company of a prior dependency on Salesforce and yielding cost savings estimated at \$150,000 per year.
- Mass-migrated the platform's microservice and front-end secrets/passwords off the internal enterprise GitHub to internal data lockboxes, closing off a primary vulnerability for internal data breaches.
- Created an extensive Jenkins-based CI/CD pipeline and testing suite for Capital One's MLaaS (Machine Learning as a Service) platform. This directly impacted continuous delivery of Capital One's primary internal machine learning platform instrumental in an estimated \$60 million in fraud reduction as of 2021.

Capstone Intern at Scientific Technologies Corporation (STC)

(August 2018 - May 2019)

- Developed REST API to interface backend Cognito authentication and database with front-end Angular web app.
- Set up CDN configuration for flexible hosting and provisioning of AWS backend resources across select regions targeted by STC to minimize usage costs.
- Created YAML scripts to automate AWS infrastructure for immediate deployment and simple scaling of the backend services using AWS CloudFormation, capable of addressing millions of STC's current or potential users.

Software Development Intern at Intel Corporation

(May 2018 - February 2019)

- Built an extensive unit-level testing framework that eliminated firmware scaling issues and improved widespread error detection across firmware for Intel Optane memory modules.
- Wrote optimizations through close communication with hardware team on detailed hardware specifications.

Undergraduate Research Assistant at CUbiC@ASU

(January 2018 - June 2018)

Developed and tested a GUI to interface with haptic sensors integrated into multiple projects aimed at guiding the visually impaired.

Software Development Intern at Arizona Supreme Court

(June 2017 - August 2017)

- Created a GUI viewing tool for querying a SQL database of court cases, streamlining front-end interaction with digital database and formatting cases to different templates based on case type.
- Created and implemented test scripts to debug the Supreme Court Case Management System, providing patches and confirming system integrity for the v.47.0 system update.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Java, C++ (proficient) Python, SQL (experienced) HTML, CSS, Javascript (experienced) Gatsby.js, GraphQL (experienced)

Platforms

Google Cloud Platform

- Google Firebase, Firestore Amazon Web Services
- Lambda, API Gateway, CloudFront, CloudFormation

EDUCATION

Barrett Honors College at Arizona State University

(Fall 2015 - Spring 2019)

BS in Computer Science

Cum Laude/ Dean's List Cumulative GPA: 3.41

PROJECTS

Scriber

An Android application that allows users to create personal medical portfolios and archive easily forgotten medical information to have easy access to in medical visits.

Viz for Spotify

A web app leveraging Spotify's web API to visualize your music and provide additional insights to enhance the music-listening experience.